BASED ON A TRUE STORY
Everything I loved in life ended .
And then life itself .
- Hello ? - Omar ?
Come here , please . I 'm on the highway , I ran over a kid .
He 's not dead , he 's not dead .
Answer me , where are you ?
What 's your name ?
Catalina , don 't take the car . It needs to be checked .
- Really ? - Yes .
On top of everything else I have to do .
It 's almost 12 o 'clock , by the way .
Your sister should be here by now .
What 's wrong ?
What 's the matter ?
Catalina , breathe !
Where are you going ?
Agata !
Sister !
No , let me go !
- Catalina ! - Let me go !
No , look at her ! Look at her ! No !
This side .
The heart stopped , help me .
No ! Agata !
No , Agata !
Emergency room .
You can 't go through . You can 't go through .
- 26 years old . - 25.75 .
25.75 !
Quickly !
- Vital signs ? - Breathing : 12 .
- Ready . - Pulse : 60 .
Impossible .
We have to amputate .
- I got her . - The saw .
kilometer 31
Relatives of Miss Hameran ?
I 'm her sister , doctor .
Catalina .
My name is Doctor Morales .
- Sit down , please . - No .
- How is my sister ? - Stable .
Thankfully she 's out of danger .
But regretfully we amputated both her legs to save her .
I 'm sorry .
There 's something else to attend right now .
Your sister went into a coma .
She 's not reacting at all .
Can I see her ?
Of course , Miss .
But
your sister 's face is very inflamed and her body is ...
Well , just be prepared .
I 'm sorry , young man .
Family members only .
Little sister .
Help me , help me .
Help me .
Miss ?
... on earth as it is in Heaven .
Give us this day our daily bread .
And forgive us our trespasses
as we forgive those who trespass against us .
And lead us not into temptation
but deliver us from evil . Amen .
Miss ? You need to rest , miss .
And the kid ?
- What kid ? - The kid my sister ran over .
We haven 't treated any kids here .
Go back home . If anything changes we 'll let you know .
Here .
They 'll help you sleep .
Never leave me .
Never forget me .
Wait for me forever .
Forgive me , my child , I didn 't know what I was doing .
I never thought that of you , never .
Don 't cry , I 'm okay .
I 'm here .
How is she ?
Bad .
- Anything else ? - Nothing . We have to wait .
- I want to see her . - You can 't go in .
I 'll be here , if anything happens I 'll tell you .
I need to go in and see her .
I told my partner I 'm going away for a few days .
You can stay at my house if you want .
It 's closer , so you don 't have to take the highway .
Thanks .
Relax .
Your sister will wake up .
I will stay at Omar 's house a few days .
It 's closer .
Okay .
Nuno , come with me to get Catalina 's things .
- Yeah , sure . - Let 's go .
Catalina ?
Yeah , I heard .
Thanks , I 'll wait for you here .
Omar , I 'm here if you need anything .
Agata always treated me well , you know .
Thanks , Nuno .
Catalina has been important in my life since I got to Mexico .
Since university .
Yeah .
Agata told me .
She 's been a good friend .
I really love her .
I can tell .
I can tell you love her .
You told her ?
That I love her ?
I show it to her .
I told her .
What the fuck are you talking about ?
Once I had a fight with Agata
and I went to her house to ask for forgiveness
and I mistook her for Catalina .
What do you expect ? They 're identical .
Sorry , they 're very different .
I want to go to the highway .
- Can you go and get her things ? - Okay , I 'll wait inside .
DRY firewood FOR SALE
Hello ?
Hey , what are you doing ?
Didn 't you hear me ? I 'm talking to you .
Fucking hell . I 'm coming !
Did you lose something ?
No .
My girlfriend had an accident
and I checked if there was anything left here .
- Sure ? - Sure about what ?
Sure you 're not looking for someone ?
How do you know ?
Don 't search , it was an accident .
I 'm in charge of the investigation .
You 're investigating ?
You could say that .
" Could say that " .
Don 't get involved in problems . Don 't investigate on your own .
Problems ? Why problems ?
Do you have a car or shall I take you ?
I just heard someone hiding back there .
Just now ?
Yes .
What 's your name ?
- Omar . - Look , Omar ...
Just concentrate on helping your girlfriend .
- I told you I heard something . - No .
Why ?
- Let me explain to you . - Don 't explain to me .
- Let me go . - I 'm talking , friend .
You know what ? Tell me your name and license plate number .
Martiin Ugalde , 02034 .
- Martiin what ? - Look .
For your own good , don 't come around here again .
Are you threatening me ?
We 're now filming .
Agata and Catalina 's birthday , June 2004 .
Here 's sister number one , look how beautiful she is .
Thank you , sweetheart .
And here is ...
There she is , sister number two .
Take a good look at her , identical .
Identical , identical . They 're talking to Nuno .
Her dear friend .
Chorizo .
Well after a couple of hours , we 're still here at the party
and as we can see , everyone is drinking .
The two sisters
drinking hard .
And
fighing , like always .
Mommy !
Don 't leave .
I 'm sorry .
I love you .
Mommy !
Don 't let her go ! .
Mommy ! .
Sister ! .
Help me !
Why did you leave the door opened ? Sorry .
I thought you 'd seen me .
Where were you ?
What are you taking ?
My pills .
What 's wrong ? Are you okay ?
No .
- Why ? - What do you want me to say ?
Okay .
Calm down , I didn 't say anything . Here 's the suitcase
and I 've bought something to eat .
There .
Nuno .
Thanks .
I know you 're trying , but
at the end , I have to do this on my own .
Yes .
I understand .
I understand you
but you 're not alone .
The doctor told us to talk .
It could be good for you .
I have so many things to say to you .
I dreamt about Mom .
She and Dad
got along better with you .
We 're equal , but
you 're better at everything .
That 's why they prefer you .
And I don 't like to admit it , but
I 'd get so angry seeing you happy .
I got angry that Dad trusted you more .
But I love you .
I love you more than I love myself .
Agata !
Agata , can you hear me ?
Agata , it 's me , Catalina !
Somebody help me , please .
- My sister woke up . - It 's okay , miss .
Apparatus , nurses .
She moved a finger and she opened her eyes .
Sorry I didn 't warn you before , Miss
but this normally happens with comatose patients .
They are electric shocks that circulate in the nervous system .
No . She saw me .
Please , believe me , Miss .
We haven 't registered any measurements
and the apparatus don 't lie .
How are you ?
- How 's Agata ? - The same ?
They 've stopped the hemorrhage . She 's still in a coma .
We have to be patient , wait a few days .
Nuno , can you take me to the highway after we eat ?
Yes , of course . To your house ?
No .
To the scene of the accident .
- What for ? - Agata ran over a kid .
- Where 's that kid ? - Catalina , there is no kid .
And there 's nothing on the highway .
I need to go .
I need to go to the scene . I can 't explain to you .
Get something to eat .
I 'll catch you up and we 'll go to the highway .
Omar ?
Don 't get them mixed up again .
- Why do you say that ? - You know why .
Are you serious ?
Everything okay ?
- What 's the matter ? - Nothing .
You know it 's incredible that
after such a long time there is so little I know about you .
- What are you talking about ? - I know a few things , but
when I ask you about yourself , things that are
important , I don 't know , it 's like you shut me out .
For example , I don 't know what happened with your parents .
- I don 't have a family . - That 's always your answer .
But why don 't you just ...
- ... let it go ? - I don 't like talking about it .
I don 't understand you .
No matter how hard I try , I don 't understand you .
I can 't do it anymore .
My Dad died in an accident .
A work accident .
On a construction site .
And my Mom
was sick .
She was schizophrenic .
She couldn 't remember which pills to take , and
my dad would get Agata to remind her .
He always trusted her more .
I don 't know why .
I felt jealous .
I gave that bottle to my mom .
It 's my fault she took too many pills and
she drowned .
Agata and I got her out of there .
We tried to revive her .
We were seven years old .
I 'm sorry . I didn 't know .
I 'm okay .
Don 't say anything to Omar .
Omar
do you prefer Nuno to drive ? You 've hardly slept .
- What 's up with you two ? - Nothing .
We 're nearly there .
Yes , I know .
When you get to km 30 , slow down .
I know . I do understand your language .
Nuno , it 's a suggestion .
A suggestion .
- Fuck that . - Why did you say that ?
Calm down , asshole , calm down .
- Don 't speak to me like that . - You 're an idiot , like earlier .
What are you talking about ? What 's up with you ?
Sorry , this fog is making me nervous .
- Fucking nervous Spaniard . - What ?
I said " Fucking nervous Spaniard " .
I heard that , but calm down , okay ? Calm down !
Watch out , Nuno !
Yes , Miss , this is an emergency .
A person 's died in the Desierto de los Leones .
Yes , hello ?
Hello ?
Yes ?
Omar , Omar Cantu .
Who 's there ?
- I 'm ... - What 's the matter ?
I talk to you , what 's wrong ?
Omar , I saw a kid .
It 's over there , I swear .
- You feeling better ? - Nuno ...
I 'll go .
It 's okay , your friends can come and pick you up .
I wasn 't my fault .
- Calm down . - Nuno .
Stay calm , you 're not under arrest .
I 'll come and get you .
You 'll make a statement at the station .
- Yes but don 't touch me , okay ? - Calm down !
Tomorrow you 'll be with your friends .
Nuno !
Leave him , leave him .
Won 't you tell me what happened ?
I heard
a woman in the street .
Last night , too .
I thought it was Agata .
Afterwards , she was shouting and crying in a sewer
inside the drain .
Why do you take those pills ?
- Why do you ask ? - Because they affect you .
No . It 's the opposite .
- Were you prescribed ? - That doesn 't matter .
I 'm not going to take them , calm down .
I won 't if you go back to the house or that highway .
Sorry .
I need to talk to you .
What about ?
What 's the matter ?
It 's just that
I can 't stop thinking about
her voice asking me for help .
When she called me , I heard everything .
The sound of the horn
the tires bursting , the bashes .
That night we had a fight .
- Surely ... - I wasn 't your fault .
I told her I wasn 't sure if I loved her .
I felt pressured .
Do you remember when I started dating her ?
I got to your house , I asked for forgiveness .
I begged you for 10 minutes .
And you
stayed silent .
You just played along .
I could never tell her the same as I did to you .
I could never tell her I loved her
that I need her , that I love her .
She knows , Omar .
She knows .
I 'm sure of it because I know it , too .
And you 're going to tell her when she wakes up .
You 're identical .
Sometimes
I 'd like to imagine you 're her .
Nuno was right .
We can get you mixed up .
Look
Nuno and I don 't get along well .
But he has a big heart .
And he loves you .
What 's up , Nacho ?
How are you ?
Garciia Castro Mariia Concepcin has identification .
This is the morgue report , I spoke to the doctor .
She has been dead for around 23 hours .
She 's been for almost a day .
The guy didn 't kill her .
He was there about 6 or 7 hours ago .
- He ran over a dead girl . - Poor guy .
He was so worried .
Let the poor guy go .
Did you report me ?
I knew .
What are you doing here ?
" An accident at kilometer 31 ...
.. on the Desierto de los Leones highway " . Again ?
Didn 't I tell you not to investigate ?
How 's your friend ?
In a coma .
Oh , kid .
Remember what I told you on the highway ?
Yes .
We 've searched for that kid .
I 've personally been searching for him for 3 years .
There have been incidents
the majority of which were related to young women .
They came in scared , badly hurt .
Sometimes they were reported dead .
They try to keep people from finding out .
They 'd called them incompetent , you know .
That 's why I keep all this under wraps . Well , that
and because it 's hard to believe .
So why were there so many accidents ?
Do you believe in ghosts ?
Ghosts ?
That 's absurd .
I can only offer you proof .
You can make your own conclusions .
Do you want to know or not ?
Please sign here .
Do you have a Biro ? A pen , sorry .
Here .
- Catalina ? - Nuno , how are you ?
Better , better .
I 'm just about to leave .
Apparently I didn 't kill her .
She 'd already been dead several hours .
Several hours ? But I saw her stood in the middle of the road .
Yes , I know .
I can 't forget it either .
Something weird 's happening , Nuno . I can 't stay like this .
What do you want to do ?
Let 's go there while it 's daytime .
Maybe it 's a kid who lives near there .
Catalina , I really don 't think we should go .
Make something up so Omar lends you his car .
But don 't tell him where we 're going .
Catalina ?
Did you see the notice ?
- Which one ? - The one back there .
- For dry firewood ? - Yes .
Do you think " El Encanto " could be a town ?
I don 't know . Why ?
Because it 's that way .
Let 's go .
What shall we do ?
Shall we knock ?
Come in , child . I was expecting you .
Who is it ?
Omar . Omar Cantu .
Afternoon .
Come in .
How are you , officer ?
Martiin . Or Ugalde , whichever you prefer .
Ugalde .
These are my darlings .
Do you like fish ?
You 're right .
Let 's get to the point .
Come through here .
You 've met my darlings .
Now let me introduce you to my obsession .
GHOST girl !
Coffee ?
Why did you say you expected me ?
I know who you are .
I know you have many questions to ask .
I also know why you came here .
Your answer is in a tragedy that occurred many years ago
and that now concerns you and your sister .
My sister ?
I told you .
It 's not a coincidence you 're here .
These are the only cases I could find from before 2001 .
But when I did the first inquiry
25 cases .
But you were saying about a tragedy .
This happened many years ago
in the colonial times , in a town near Mexico City .
In that town there was a young woman of impressive beauty
who a Spanish serviceman fell in love with and cheated on
using her to inbreed the children his wife couldn 't have .
When she found out , the young woman went mad with anger
and she threw herself into the river with her child
dragging him behind her
to their death .
Since then , the souls of the woman and child
have been condemned to wander by the rivers .
Mainly young women are found with them .
The mother 's pain is heard as she cries out for her dead son .
Some live to tell the tale
others don 't .
If this was true , there would be
there would be ghosts everywhere !
Maybe not everywhere , but
take a look at this .
- I heard that woman . - Where ?
In Riio Mixcoac .
Shouting and grumbling like you described .
Did you see the kid , too ?
Do you have more information about the woman in Mixcoac ?
Yes , actually , several cases .
" February 19th , 1999 , Avenida Riio Mixcoac :
High school students reported having heard
a woman trapped in the drains " .
Why the curiosity about Mixcoac ?
I live near there and my sister in-law told me
she heard a woman around there .
I didn 't understand but now ...
But now you believe me , right ?
Here I have a map .
Look
your sister suffers pain that doesn 't correspond to her .
There 's nothing that can help her .
Neither prayers , nor sacrifices , nothing .
But
maybe your sister could help .
How ?
She 's trapped between the two worlds
but you have the bond with your sister .
So you too can see the other world
and bring it to you and to those around you .
What worlds ?
The world of the living ...
- ... and the world of the dead . - Excuse me , but
from what I know , it hasn 't been proven that ghosts exist .
But there are people who say they 've seen them .
Do you think they 're lying ?
No .
Not necessarily .
Only a sensitive and noble spirit is capable of
hearing and seeing a soul in pain .
But be careful .
There are spirits that can transform what you see
and they could help you .
But they could also trick you just like any person can .
But it 's dark now
and I don 't want you to be in any danger .
Catalina , you can stay in the bedroom .
And you , Nuno , you can sleep by the chimney .
We 're not staying , are we ?
- She looks really trustworthy . - lt was a good story , but ...
- ... do you really believe it ? - I heard that woman .
- Catalina ... - It 's true , Nuno .
Agata is stuck in that world .
I can feel it . She 's telling me .
I dream about that .
Catalina ?
This can 't be .
No , this can 't be !
Catalina , this is Omar , call me , this is urgent .
I met somebody who ... Well , you 're right .
We have to find that woman .
In the drainage in Riio Mixcoac .
There 's an opening near my house , call me , please .
Sorry I didn 't believe you .
Catalina ?
Nuno ?
Hey
it 's dangerous here .
Here . I 'll go back in my car .
Catalina !
... the Lord is with thee .
Blessed art thou among women
and blessed is the fruit of thy womb , Jesus .
Holy Mary , Mother of God
pray for us sinners now
and at the hour of death . Amen .
Hail Mary , Full of Grace . The Lord is with thee ...
Mystic Rose , pray for them .
Tower of David , pray for them .
Ivory Tower , pray for them .
Golden House , pray for them .
Ark of the Covenant , pray for them .
Gates of Heaven , pray for them .
Nuno ?
What ?
That day ...
- You haven 't slept , have you ? - I 'll sleep later .
Good morning , guys .
- I 'll make you some coffee . - Thanks , but we 're going now .
It 's no bother . I 'm always alone .
- Here , you dropped it . - Thanks .
- I didn 't hear you go out . - You stayed awake , right ?
You 're right in not wanting to sleep .
When you sleep you 're more sensitive , more open .
Maybe it 'll help to be close to your sister .
Ask her advice .
Sleep , and she will guide us .
Maybe you have to go back and meet that woman
or her spirit .
Look further than your eyes let you see .
Sorry , ma 'am , but ...
- ... what are you talking about ? - You have to be strong .
Help us , even if you don 't understand .
Take care . Fight .
Defend yourself .
- What are you doing ? - Looking at things Omar left .
- Where did he get all this from ? - I don 't know .
- But I think I understand now . - Shall I help you ?
Didn 't you want to see your sister ?
Nuno
thanks for everything .
I thought about lots of things and
and I thought about all these years .
And ...
- ... I don 't know . - No .
- Let me tell you ... - Catalina .
Not now .
This isn 't the time , you 're
under a lot of pressure .
It 's not a good time .
Okay .
Look .
Look at this old map .
The lady said it happened in the colonial times .
I compared it with an updated map .
Come on .
Look how small it was , the size of the central square .
The old town of Coyoacan was here
which is now the current area of Coyoacan you know .
This is where the river is .
Look at the new map .
It goes straight down what is now this avenue , Mixcoac .
Of course .
Riio Mixcoac .
And this river crosses the Desierto de los Leones .
They cross almost the same points .
Maybe the lady was right about what she said about
looking further than your eyes let you .
ELDERLY LADY TAKES HER OWN life
What ? Did you see something ?
No . I 'm going to see my sister .
Shall I come with you ?
Catalina ?
Omar ?
Omar , what 's happened to you ? Omar , what 's happened ?
Omar , you 're scaring me , answer me , please !
Omar !
What happened , Omar ?
What happened to you , Omar ? Answer me !
Where are we going ?
Omar ?
Omar , answer me , goddamnit ! Answer me !
Where are we going , Omar ?
What are we doing here ?
Yes . I 'm calling to report
a dead person .
Kilometer 31 , Desierto de los Leones Highway .
No , I don 't want to leave my name .
Message received today :
Catalina , this is Omar , call me , this is urgent .
I met somebody who ... Well , you 're right .
We have to find that woman .
In the drainage in Rio Mixcoac .
There 's an opening near my house .
I come to find you on the highway .
Call me , please .
They won 't beat me .
You won 't beat me , you won 't beat me .
I can 't ...
I can 't do this , I can 't do this anymore .
I 'm not frightened .
I 'm not , I 'm not , I 'm not in my mind .
Agata 's with me . I 'll help her .
She needs me .
We 're not different . We 're the same .
We are one .
Frighteningly equal .
I 'm not
in my mind .
Shit !
Taxi !
To the Desierto de los Leones highway .
Affirmative , it 's kilometer 31 .
Desierto de los Leones highway .
Affirming 84 , highway 76 . 20 , over .
- What happened ? - He was run over last night .
Last night ?
Where did you find him ?
Over there , next to the shoulder , in the bushes .
- Did you see a young woman here ? - Woman ? No . Please go away .
Excuse me , officer .
- What is the name of the victim ? - Omar Cantu .
Excuse me .
- Do you know who Omar is ? - Yes , I knew him .
- Who are you ? - I 'm ...
We were friends .
Of course , the one from the station .
I 'm Martiin Ugalde . I was with Omar yesterday .
- I showed him some files . - Files ?
I saw them , too .
There 's something strange .
The river still exists , just like the lady said .
What are you talking about ?
An elderly lady who lives in an old house near here .
- Show me . - I don 't have time now .
- I have to look for a friend . - You can do that later .
This can 't be true .
It 's here , isn 't it ?
An elderly woman lived here .
But she committed suicide on the highway .
That happened in the 1940s .
She told Catalina
to look ...
Help me find her , please .
Catalina 's sure she can communicate with her sister
it 's something they 've always done .
The lady said something about asking for help .
And do you know exactly where in Mixcoac ?
Yes . Well , more or less . Omar marked it in a map .
It 's near her house .
Of course , I marked that map .
Sleep .
Why did you do this to me , child ?
I 'm not crazy . Calm down .
Mommy 's here .
Calm down . Why did you do it to me ?
No , child .
It must be around here .
There 's the car !
There !
Don 't move .
Miss !
Officer !
Catalina !
Hello , child .
We 're here now .
I came to help , my child .
It 's the only way to end this .
And to help your sister .
Are you ready to sacrifice yourself for her ?
I tried . I sacrificed myself for him .
But it didn 't work .
It didn 't work because the kid didn 't die
where the highway is now .
The river took him away .
But they died here .
My sacrifice should have been done here .
I now that know
thanks to you
and to your sister .
Who are you ?
My kid .
Leave Agata alone .
Where 's my kid ?
I know where he is .
But leave my sister in peace .
Don 't leave me here , child .
Don 't be afraid .
I 've been expecting you .
I 'm sorry , Mom .
There 's nothing to be sorry about .
Come , child ...
Don 't worry .
Don 't be afraid .
Don 't worry , don 't worry , don 't worry .
My child
all this will be over soon .
Catalina !
It 's me , Nuno !
It 's okay .
I 'll never leave you . Never , never .
It 's over , it 's over .
Calm down .
- What 's wrong ? - Where are we ?
In the sewers .
What 's wrong ?
What 's the matter ?
Nuno , why are you looking at me like that ?
- Who are you ? - It 's me .
- Catalina . - You 're not Catalina !
Catalina ?
Drop your weapon !
Drop it ! Now !
Nuno .
What 's wrong with you ?
You have to do it .
Nuno !
It 's the only way .
You have to finish it .
Nuno !
Put the weapon down !
Nuno .
Catalina ...
Everything I loved in life ended .
And then life itself .
What 's happened ?
Hey ...
Where am I ?
Calm down .
You 're in a hospital .
What happened ?
Where 's Catalina ?
It 's a good thing you 're here .
He woke up in the early hours with changes .
I gave him 15mg of Diazepam during the night .
Has he calmed down ?
Where 's Catalina ?
Catalina is dead .
You killed her .
Don 't you remember ?
What are you saying ?
- lt can 't be true . - What did you see ?
Who did you see ?
I have to see her !
- What 's this ? - It 's for your safety .
Until you get better . You 're going to need help .
I have to see Catalina .
Untie me .
I said untie me !
Where 's Catalina ?
Untie me !
Thank you .
Agata .
Miss Hameran ?
Hello , Agata .
Where am I ?
In a hospital .
Don 't strain yourself
your memory will come back slowly .
Where is he ?
Where 's my child ?
- What child ? - My child . My child .
You don 't have any children , Miss .
- Where 's my child ? - Don 't get upset .
- Don 't get upset . - Where 's my child ?
Nurse !
- Where 's my child ? - Nurse !
Where 's my child ?